<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course Grading | STA 216</title>
    <link>https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Course Grading</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://stat216.github.io/media/sta216-sticker.png</url>
      <title>Course Grading</title>
      <link>https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessments</title>
      <link>https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/assessments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Assessments will include Individual and Team Preparations, Quizzes, Homework, and Exams.
As part of these assessments, you will be asked to upload documents to Blackboard, take tests via Blackboard, create videos and upload these into Blackboard, and upload documents to a Google Drive folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-membership&#34;&gt;Course Membership&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Components in this category can take many forms including an introductory video you create/submit, weekly check-ins, active participation in the class, and reflections on your learning.
In no way, however, will this component be a direct reflection of class attendance.
One planned component is explained below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check-in&lt;/strong&gt;: We are each being impacted by and dealing with the current Covid-19 crisis in different ways.
Nearly every week I will ask you to submit a short response to a prompt on what you are doing to cope during these times.
Each week will be slightly different with respect to what you are submitting, but you will typically provide some form of media (a single word, emoji, animated GIF, meme, image of a piece of art, song, etc.) and write a brief explanation for your selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to doing weekly check-ins in this course, I have partnered with six other faculty from across campus to do similar check-ins within their courses.
Responses from these courses will be combined and summarized.
We will spend portions of class time discussing these responses from students around GVSU.
To facilitate this, you will submit your responses in a Google Form (shared with you on Blackboard) that requires you to login with your GVSU network account.
None of your personally identifiable information (e.g., name) will be shared with other students; however, your responses to these prompts will be viewable by other students.
Additionally, students in some of these courses will use the combined, de-identified data for class projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Check-in will be worth 1 point and your submission will be graded on whether your response is thoughtful, well-written, and shows engagement with the prompt.
Notice that this is essentially a completion-based system.
I am not grading your writing ability and I am not counting the exact number of words you are writing.
I am looking for thoughtful engagement, that is all.
Do good work and you will earn the point.
If you prefer to not have your responses available to students outside of the class, contact your professor for an alternative assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;individual-preparation-quizzes&#34;&gt;Individual Preparation Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Learning Module will begin with completion of an Individual Preparation quiz.
An Individual Preparation quiz will be administered via Blackboard and typically composed of approximately twelve questions (multiple-choice, short answer, etc.) based on the assigned Learning Module readings.
An Individual Preparation score will be based on the number of correct answers.
You will have up to three attempts for each Individual Preparation; the score from the last attempt completed prior to the submission deadline will be recorded as you grade.
Each Individual Preparation will consist of randomly-generated items so one attempt will likely differ from the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-preparation-discussions&#34;&gt;Team Preparation Discussions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Preparation discussions will be completed using the Discussion Board feature within the group space in Blackboard.
Grading will be primarily based on timeliness of a response and whether the content of the response is substantive.
For each Learning Module, you are required to start a discussion (by a specified deadline) and to add to at least one discussion (by another specified deadline) which were started by other team members.
Each Team Preparation is worth up to four points (up to two points related to the starting of a discussion and up to two points related to the adding to a discussion started by a fellow team members).&lt;br&gt;
Team Preparation contributions must be “substantive postings” (of both quality and reasonable length).
For instance, when you add to a discussion topic, statements of simple agreement in response to a topic (i.e., “I agree” or “Good answer”) lack substantive content; your added comment should further the discussion of the prompt topic in a substantial way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-quizzes&#34;&gt;Application Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the semester, there will be (at least) 20 Application Quizzes.
Typically, an Application Quiz is attached to an activity and will be administered as a test via Blackboard.
Whereas Individual and Team Preparations can thought of as a Learning Module pre-test, an Application Quiz can be viewed as a post-test for an activity.
An Application Quiz is designed as a way to assess your understanding of the ontent in an activity prior to attempting Homework.
An Application Quiz will typically be assigned at the end of a class session and due 2 hours before the next class session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their collective importance, the completion of an Application Quiz is optional.
Application Quizzes are not part of the regular course points used to determine the base letter grade.
However, the completion or non-completion of the Application Quiz can impact the final semester grade that is reported (see &lt;a href=&#34;courses/course-grading/grading/&#34;&gt;Grade Determination&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework&#34;&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten homework assignments are planned.
SAS-program-based homework will be uploaded into a shared Google folder.
Homework involving interpretations and explanation will be completed as a “test” via Blackboard.
Homework will be graded; however, not all assigned questions, in part or partial, may factor into the homework grade.
Only the top eight homework scores will be used in determining course grades.
The exact dates of a homework will be announced at least one week in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exams&#34;&gt;Exams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be five examinations – one corresponding to each Learning Module.
The due date/time for the semester examinations will be announced at least a week in advance.
An exam may include a portion completed via a Blackboard Test (multiple-choice, short answer, etc.) and a portion that involves submission of a video recording of yourself (both visual and auditory) explaining answers to provided prompts based on a scenario.
You will have a window of time (typically at least 48 hours) in which complete and submit an examination.
The portion of an exam completed as a Blackboard Test will be time limited.
There will also be a maximum time limit imposed on any video portion of an exam.
More details about the specifics of an exam, including when it is due, will be provided prior to each examination.
You will upload any document used in guiding your completion of the video portion of an examination in Blackboard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grade Determination</title>
      <link>https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stat216.github.io/courses/course-grading/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We use a weighted grading system in this course.
Although individual grade components will have points attached, the weight will be used to determine course grades.
Grades will be maintained in Blackboard so you can determine your current grade at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Source&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Weighted Percent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Class Membership&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Individual Preparation (top 4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Team Preparation (top 4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Homework (top 8)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exams (5 total)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-grade&#34;&gt;Final Grade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your course grade is determined using two steps.
First, your &lt;strong&gt;base grade&lt;/strong&gt; (The letter A, B, C, D, or F &lt;em&gt;without plus or minus&lt;/em&gt;) is determined using the table provided below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Criteria&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Base Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;≥ 90.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;≥ 80.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;≥ 70.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;≥ 60.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;lt; 60.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, once your base grade has been determined, a plus/minus distinction may be added to your base grade.
Note that I cannot award an &amp;ldquo;A+&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;D-&amp;rdquo; since these grades do not exist at GVSU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;plus&lt;/strong&gt; (+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A “plus” may be added to your base grade if you have earned at least 80% of the Application Quiz points &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; earned at least an 80% on Exam 5.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;minus&lt;/strong&gt; (-)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A “minus” may be added to your base grade if you have earned less than 60% of the Application Quiz points &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; earned less than 60% on Exam 5.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errors in Grading&lt;/strong&gt;:  While I strive for grading accuracy, mistakes in grading may still occur.
If you feel a mistake in grading has occurred (i.e. grade entry error, calculation error), alert me within one week from when the grade in question was entered into Blackboard.
After a week has passed following entry of a grade, I will assume that any entered grade is correct unless you communicate to me otherwise.
As such, it is important that you take ownership of your grade throughout the semester!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
